<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>registration on Bobble Law</title><link>https://bobblelaw.github.io/tags/registration/</link><description>Recent content in registration on Bobble Law</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 &lt;a href="#">Bobble Law&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="#">Stay Inc.&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 16:37:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bobblelaw.github.io/tags/registration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Perspective-N-Points</title><link>https://bobblelaw.github.io/posts/understanding-pnp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 16:37:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bobblelaw.github.io/posts/understanding-pnp/</guid><description>Introduction The Perspective-n-Point (PnP) problem is the problem of estimating the relative pose between an object and the camera, given a set of correspondences between 3D points and their projections on the image plane. It is a fundamental problem that was first studied in the photogrammetry literature, and later on studied in the context of computer vision.
In this post, I will present a few solvers (among many), discuss their proofs and also show some concise implementations.</description></item><item><title>Review on Points Registration</title><link>https://bobblelaw.github.io/posts/brief-review-on-points-registration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 22:52:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://bobblelaw.github.io/posts/brief-review-on-points-registration/</guid><description>If you have looked into the principles behind any 3D sensors, you will find they always fall into the following catagory.
Here we are not interested into contact-based methods, because they usually need clumsy devices and tedious acquisition process. No offense, their are super accurate compare to vision-based methods, if you can afford them.
For vision-based 3D scanning. There are active and passive.
Concept Scene Project light coded pattern or stripe to the object. Obeserve the geometry changes of patterns.</description></item></channel></rss>